Alexinder Virdee

Miami, FL | (954) 616-9029 | alex@virdee.com

<u>alexvirdee.com</u> | <u>LinkedIn.com/in/alexvirdee</u> | <u>github.com/alexvirdee</u>

Profile

I am a Fort Lauderdale based software developer who loves technology. Obtaining my bachelor's degree at the University of Central Florida I work hard to solve difficult problems. I have several years of experience working in an array of industries such as healthcare and aviation related software development. I am excited, and look forward to opportunities that will contribute to the continuous development of my skills and passion for software development.

Technical Skills

JavaScript, Angular, Express.js, MongoDB, SQL, Node.js, SPARQL, RDF, Ember, React, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, AJAX, Responsive Design, Tailwinds, Bootstrap, Git, GitHub, Wordpress, Typescript, ILE RPG, Profound.js.

Professional Experience

Software Developer

August 2020 - Present

Banyan Air Service

Fort Lauderdale, FL

• Successfully completed ILE RPG training from IMPower Technologies in an intensive training environment becoming skilled in IBM related systems in a short time-frame

Web Application Developer

April 2018 - January 2020

INFOTECHSoft, Inc.

Miami. FL

- Tasked to the GeneTegra Platform Data Lakes and Baptist Health Projects committed to advancing biomedical research in the health-care industry
- Utilized semantic web technologies such as SPARQL, RDF, and OWL to aggregate and query vast amounts of biomedical data
- Prepared and developed UX/UI mockup proposals using Balsamiq wireframing software successfully iterating, creating, and producing client specific designs
- Tasked with developing and enhancing features for company applications primarily with the JavaScript web development framework Ember.js
- Kept legacy applications up to date implementing latest versions and testing code with QUnit
- Skilled in the software development life cycle, achieving excellent quality of applications by appropriately employing Kanban methodology

Teaching Assistant

May 2018 - August 2018

University of Miami

Miami, FL

- Worked closely with students to help them understand and program the basic fundamentals of JavaScript and front-end technologies
- Developed trust and rapport with class to code applications starting with design and building REST APIs with NodeJS & front-end user interfaces with React

Education

Ironhack

January 2018 - March 2018

Miami. FL

• Ironhack is an immersive web development bootcamp. The program has a fast paced setting with a highly selective cohort of students.

Projects Built

- Paper Droid An interactive JavaScript based arcade shooter game with collision logic
- <u>Divex</u> Server side scuba diving web application with user authorization to log dive experiences
- M5Power A BMW forums application for enthusiasts of the BMW M series (MEAN Stack)
- <u>Howlongtoread</u> (In-progress) React application interacting with Google Books and New York Times APIs

University of Central Florida

August 2012 - August 2016

Orlando. FL